# Will Turnage

Principal System Administrator (601) 345-9968 will.turnage@icloud.com

### **SUMMARY**

Over ten years of System Administrative experience with UNIX/Linux operating systems, and F5 BigIP Platform. Currently working remotely as a Principal System Administrator for Vanderbilt University where my primary responsibilities are Linux, F5, and Kubernetes Administration.

### **SKILLS**

AWS, Ansible, Tower, Red Hat Satellite Server, Python 2.7, Python 3, bash, git, puppet, SaltStack, VMware ESXi, AIX, POWER7, Solaris, Linux, Debian, Red Hat, CentOS, SUSE, NGINX, Apache, NFS, SSSD, LDAP, Nagios, Ganglia, Grafana, Splunk, Kubernetes, Rancher, Infoblox, haproxy, F5 Big-IP, LTM, GTM, APM.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

Principal System Administrator

July 2021 - Present: Vanderbilt University, Remote

- Team Lead of a group of Linux/F5/Kubernetes administrators responsible for fulfilling the expectations of a Sr System Administrator in addition to providing technical expertise for critical Enterprise systems and mentoring colleagues.
- Deployed Rancher Kubernetes clusters and coordinated application migrations off deprecated clusters.
- Implemented F5's BigIP Kubernetes ingress controller.
- Integrated SaltStack API solution to receive calls from Embotics vCommander Cloud Manager to deploy Linux Servers.
- Developed Python3 program to integrate metrics collection of F5, K8S, and Infoblox APIs to present in Microsoft Power BI.

### Sr System Administrator

March 2016 - June 2021: Vanderbilt University, Nashville, Tennessee

- Member of a team of Linux and F5 administrators responsible for working with customers and project management teams to design and develop a high quality, automated solution that is configurable, scalable, and monitorable.
- Migrated PINGFederate infrastructure from on premise to AWS.
- Deployed F5 BigIP APM and developed policies for legacy applications to comply with MFA policy.
- Deployed Kubernetes Cluster for mission critical student facing applications.
- Developed automation process for patching Facilities climate control systems.
- Developed Python program to integrate Cherwell ITSM and Monitoring Tool Nagios to manage and escalate alerts.
- Deployed Infoblox Cloud appliances in AWS and utilized Global Accelerator to improve query times of External DNS.
- Migrated BIND DNS servers to vendor supported Infoblox Grid.
- Migrated F5 BigIP hardware platforms from Viprions to vCMPs with no downtime or customer impact.

# System Administrator

November 2014 - February 2016: Vanderbilt University Medical Center, Nashville, Tennessee

- Member of a team of UNIX/Linux and F5 administrators responsible for Patient Care Services.
- Deployed IBM License Metric Tool.
- Setup new BIND servers to replace legacy DNS equipment.
- Brought AIX environment to a supported firmware and patch level, and consolidated production HMC hardware.
- Migrated Red Hat Satellite 5 to Satellite Server 6.
- Fully automated patching process using Ansible playbooks.
- Setup new F5 BigIP GTMs and LTMs in preparation for the operational splitting of the medical center and university infrastructure

# System Administrator II

July 2010 - September 2014: C Spire, Ridgeland, Mississippi

- Member of a team of UNIX/Linux system administrators and SAN/Storage administrators responsible for Business Critical Systems and Customer Facing Services.
- Responsible for maintaining the continued operation of business critical IBM AIX, Sun Solaris and Linux production Fujitsu, IBM Blade Centers, IBM POWER Systems and Dell servers, and responsible for the research and development of future production systems for IT Infrastructure.
- Deployed Enterprise Splunk Cluster and migrated data from a single node instance.
- Team lead for the Solaris to AIX Oracle Database migration. I was recognized internally after the project was complete.
- Successfully designed and deployed open source Puppet for over 300 nodes.
- Veritas Cluster Services and Fujitsu Prime Cluster systems administrator for the business critical clustered applications and file services.
- Veritas Storage Foundation and Solaris Volume Manager administrator.
- VMware vSphere infrastructure administrator.

### **EDUCATION and CERTIFICATION**

- University of Southern Mississippi Hattiesburg, MS
  Bachelors of Sciences in Information Technology 2010
- Red Hat Certified System Engineer (RHCE)

December 2015 - December 2018

• VMware Certified Professional 6 - Data Center Virtualization (VCP6-DCV)

November 2018 - Present